翻译/压制/字幕：HAF半个水果    翻译支持：DeepL
原始字幕来自YouTube，如有错漏，欢迎指正！
大家好，我是 Ossy Flawol
Hey everyone, the name's Ossy Flawol.
传送门系列是一款第一人称解谜游戏，你要利用传送门
The Portal series is a first person puzzle game that involves you utilising Portals
解决测试房间的问题。大家都知道这一点。除了各种各样的解谜机制之外，
to solve Test Chambers. Everyone knows this. Alongside its wide variety of puzzle mechanics,
传送门最经典的谜题机制之一就是利用重力本身,
one of Portal's most classic puzzle mechanics is the act of utilising gravity itself,
通过传送门创建与动量守恒相关的操作，
creating manoeuvres related to the conservation of momentum through Portals,
你可以通过一个传送门，并以同样的速度
where you can drop through a Portal, and come speeding out the other end at the same speed to
从另一端飞快地跑出来,制造处所谓的“抛出”
launch yourself through the air, creating what is known as the iconic 'Flinging'.
1. 利用动量守恒，通过传送门在空中飞行的行为
名词
这种物理的实现方式要归功于起源引擎的标志性物理特性
This implementation of physics in this manner is thanks to the Source Engine's iconic physics
基于Havok的Ipion虚拟物理的引擎，该引擎演变成了VPhysics
engine based off of Havok's Ipion Virtual Physics, which evolved into the VPhysics
引进起源中。众所周知，这个物理引擎负责有趣的
Engine once implemented into Source. This physics engine is responsible for the funny
布娃娃效果，这个视频的主题 - 传送门的物理特性
ragdolls that Source is all well known for, and on topic for this video - Portal's physics.
为了把一些技术性的东西说清楚，传送门
To get some technical stuff out of the way, the Portals in the portal franchise
与VPhysics进行了独特的互动，因为它带来了很多技术性的挑战，
interact uniquely with VPhysics, as it presents a lot of technical challenges,
如果你有兴趣了解，游戏中的开发者评论会解释很多
the developer commentary ingame explains a lot if you're interested in learning the
传送门团队是如何让VPhysics与传送门互动的细枝末节
nitty gritty of how it was like for the Portal team to get VPhysics interacting with Portals
传送门背后的一般编程基本上完全改变了
nicely. The general programming behind Portals was basically entirely changed for the sequel
when it was reprogrammed to be better optimised and more stable, allowing for moving portals,
它被重新编程为取得更好的优化和更稳定性，允许移动传送门
并让像Xbox 360这样的低端硬件能够渲染多达16个传送门
and letting lower end hardware like the Xbox 360 be capable of rendering up to 16 portals
这是在分屏玩合作游戏时实现的壮举
at once - a feat achieved by playing the Cooperative Campaign in split screen and
更正：总共有32个传送门
（我没有朋友一起玩)
所有4个传送门都是可见的，并且通过传送门本身有一定程度的递归
having all 4 portals visible and a level of recursion through the Portals themselves.
所以，现在我们已经澄清了这一点，而且每个人都
So, now that we have that cleared up and everyone
在同一起点上 - 这是故事真正开始的地方
now on the same page - this is where the story really starts.
2011年6月22日，在一次关于教育和电子游戏如何协同工作的谈话中
On the 22nd of June, 2011, during a talk about how education and video games could work in tandem,
G胖在2011年的游戏变革节上突然出现，宣布
Gabe Newell popped up at the Games For Change Festival of 2011 to announce that Portal 2 would
《传送门2》将进入课堂--免费，而且Valve公司正在积极地创建基于《传送门2》的一个课程，
be coming to Classrooms - for free, and that Valve was actively working on creating a curriculum that
这当然引起了一些人的注意， 当人们
would be based around utilising Portal 2. This certainly raised a few eyebrows, as people were
对这可能导致的结果感到好奇时，一年后，在2012年的游戏变革节上，
intrigued by what this could lead to, and a year later at the Games For Change Festival for 2012,
Valve终于展示了他们正在研究的东西--Steam For Schools
Valve finally showed what they were working on - Steam For Schools.
Valve公司一直在与教育部门的人合作，
Valve had been working with people in the educational sector to design a whole
围绕《传送门2》和它在课堂上的应用设计整个课程，
curriculum based all around Portal 2 and its application in the classroom,
它的最终结果是创造Steam For Schools，这是一个旨在
and the end result of it came Steam For Schools, being a stripped down version
用于学校教育环境的精简版Steam，以及传送门2教育版，
of Steam intended to be used in schooling environments, and Portal 2 Educational Version,
一个专门的传送门2版本，将被更新和维护，以便在课堂上使用
a specialised version of Portal 2 that would be updated and maintained for use in the classroom.
传送门2已经通过Valve的Teach With Portals项目进入了教室，
Portal 2 had entered classrooms through Valve's Teach With Portals program,
旨在帮助学校和教师在课堂上使用传送门2的计划，
a program designed to help schools and teachers utilise Portal 2 in the classroom
通过访问Steam For Schools和提供课程计划来使用，
via giving access to Steam For Schools and providing Lesson Plans to be used, all mostly
所有这些都主要围绕着物理和数学科目。我想应该还有一个英语课
focused around the subjects of Physics and Maths. Oh, and a single English lesson plan I guess.
这些教案读起来相当有趣，工作表和其它所需都有提供，
These lesson plans are pretty interesting to read through, worksheets and all are provided,
我喜欢这些底部带有光圈科学标志的东西，
I love how these are all branded with the Aperture Science logo on the bottom,
这给我带来了一个巨大而愚蠢的微笑，因为试图想象
it brings me a big dumb smile on my face because trying to imagine
自己作为一个学生去做这些事情，几乎肯定会导致
myself as a student getting to do these would almost certainly result
学生我在课堂上过度紧张。对你来说是这样的
in student me hyperventilating in the middle of class. Hyperfixations do that to you.
那么，《传送门2》究竟是如何在课堂上使用的呢？好吧，如果我
So how was Portal 2 actually used in the classroom? Well, if I was
是在一周左右前制作这个视频，我就没有办法打开教育版，
making this video a week or so ago, I wouldn't have any way to open the Educational Version
因为唯一存在的下载是被锁在Steam上的正版拷贝
since the only download that exists of it is a genuine copy that's locked behind a Steam
更正一下：这实际上是一个可怕的
基础传送门2
和传送门2教育版的合并版本
是学校账户专供，但要感谢wertercatt和Christsnatcher的努力，
For School accounts, but thanks to the efforts of wertercatt and Christsnatcher,
传送门2的教育版有史以来第一次被破解，现在可以尽情游玩了
Portal 2's Educational Version was cracked open for the first time ever and is now playable.
现在，先声明一下--我不会提供教育版破解版的下载链接，因为
Now, to preface - I won't be providing a download link to the Educational Version crack, as it's
TLDR-我在法律上不能提供这个东西的下载，
否则会使我的频道陷入麻烦。
这简直就是一个没有Steam的免费版《传送门2》，我不会
literally a free version of Portal 2 that works without Steam and I'm not here to promote piracy
在这个频道上宣传盗版，因为那会给我带来麻烦，去买《传送门2》吧，
on this channel because that can get me into trouble, go buy Portal 2 you twerp, it's as low
它在Steam的销售中低至2美元，是有史以来最好的视频游戏之一，你绝不会后悔
as 2 dollars on Steam's sales and one of the best video games ever made, you'll never regret it.
总之，让我们讨论一下教育版的实际内容，
Anyways, let's discuss the actual content of the Educational Version,
我们将使用其在Valve默默停止支持之前的最新版本
we'll be using its latest version before Valve stopped supporting it silently.
在主菜单上，你已经可以看到一些明显的区别，按钮
Already on the main menu you can see some clear differences. The buttons
进行双人合作，附加内容和机器人自定义都被移除
for the Cooperative Campaign, Extras Menu, and Robot Enrichment have all been removed,
只留下进行单人游戏、Puzzlemaker、选项和退出按钮
leaving only the Singleplayer Campaign, Puzzlemaker, Options, and Exit Button.
尽管删除了选项，但这些东西仍有完整的功能。合作模式仍可使用，
Despite the removed options, these things still have full functionality. Coop is still playable
这是我强迫游戏加载一个分屏合作比赛
如果你直接加载，附加内容菜单中的Super 8 Teaser也保持不变
if you load directly into it, and the Super 8 Teaser from the Extras menu remains intact.
说到单人游戏，一切都与原来的游戏基本相同
When it comes to the Singleplayer Campaign, everything is basically the same as the original game.
英语教案实际上要求玩单人游戏，
The English lesson plan actually requires the singleplayer campaign to
以便分析故事，这也说明了为什么它仍然是完整的
be played in order to analyse the story, which makes sense why it's still intact.
然而，教育版真正令人感兴趣的是Puzzlemaker。这个Puzzlemaker
The real intrigue for the Educational Version however is the Puzzlemaker. This puzzlemaker
绝对是令人着迷的，因为它是专门为Teach With Portals项目制作的独特版本
is absolutely fascinating due to the fact that it's a unique version made
Puzzlemaker包含了三个专门用于Teach With Portals项目的谜题。Puzzlemaker包含三个
specifically for the Teach With Portals program. The puzzlemaker contains three
新的项目--Contraption Cube, Contraption Button, 和Text Bubble
new items - the Contraption Cube, Contraption Button, and Text Bubble.
Contraption Cube是一个全新的立方体，专门为教育版制作，
The Contraption Cube is an entirely new cube made specifically for the Education Version,
独一无二，因为有三个新的选项。你可以在天平上改变立方体的重量，
unique for having three new options. You can change the weight of the cube on a scale from
从1公斤到80公斤，在5个不同的预设之间改变其摩擦力，
1 kilogram to 80 kilograms, change its friction between 5 different presets,
是85Kg，说错了
并改变其弹性，也是在5种不同的预设之间
and change its elasticity, also between 5 different presets.
根据你设定的重量，Contraption Cube
Depending on the weight you set the cube to, the weight ball inside the Contraption
内部的重量球实际上会改变大小以适应它。一个1公斤的立方体里面有
Cube will actually change size to accommodate for it. A cube of 1 kilogram features a tiny
一个小小的重量球，而一个最大重量为85公斤的东西，其整个内部
weight ball inside it, while a max weight one at 85 kilograms will have its entire
将被重量球所覆盖。这实际上是通过flex group动态完成的，
interior encompassed by the weight ball. This is actually done dynamically via a flex group
类似于起源引擎中面部动画的完成方式，这真的很酷。改变
similar to how facial animations are done in the Source Engine, which is really cool. Changing the
立方体的重量将使它对重力做出不同的反应，较轻的立方体下降得较慢，
weight of the cube will make it react differently in response to gravity, lighter cubes fall slower,
而更重的立方体在空气中的下落速度更快，它们的下落速度似乎随着
and heavier cubes drop faster through the air, the speed at which they drop seems to decrease
它们的变重而呈指数级下降，这里有一个快速测试，证明了这种行为
exponentially as they get heavier, here's a quick test demonstrating this behaviour.
默认情况下，Contraption Cube是无摩擦的，这意味着它在任何
The Contraption Cube by default is frictionless, meaning it will experience zero drag on any
光滑的表面上都会遇到零阻力，并像在冰上一样无休止地滑动。正如预期的那样，增加
surfaces it slides along and slide endlessly as if it's on ice. As expected, upping the friction
立方体的摩擦力会使它不那么容易滑动。摩擦力增加的程度由这些垫子表示，
on the cube will make it less slide-y. The levels of friction addition are indicated by these pads
它们被添加到立方体的白色外表上，它们随着每个摩擦力的预设而增加，直到
that get added onto the cube's white exterior, they build up with each Friction preset until
最后垫子完全覆盖白色部分。下面是一个快速演示
the final one where the pads entirely cover the white parts. Here's a quick demonstration.
Contraption Cube的弹性控制了立方体的弹跳力，
The elasticity of the Contraption Cube controls how bouncy the cube is,
这可以通过握住或移动立方体时的抖动程度来表示，
this is indicated by how much the Cube seems to jiggle when held or moved,
以及白色的外部部分是如何与立方体分离的。在这里，
and how separated the white exterior parts become from the cube. Here,
我在从非常有弹性到没有反弹的范围内进行了一次跌落测试，所以你可以分辨出其中的差别
I perform a drop test on a scale from Very Bouncy to No Rebound so you can tell the difference.
现在，很明显，你可以根据自己的意愿混合和匹配这些设置，
Now, obviously, you can mix and match these settings to your heart's desire,
我相信总共有大约
in total I believe there's approximately
约2100个潜在的独特装置方块设置
2100个独特的Contraption Cube设置，存在它的可定制性
2,100 unique Contraption Cube settings that exist with the customisability of it,
使其成为《传送门2》中最多样化的官方测试元素，恭喜Contraption Cube!
making it Portal 2's most diverse official Testing Element, congratulations Contraption Cube!
Contraption Cube也有自己的配套按钮，即Contraption Button
The Contraption Cube also has its own accompanying button, being the Contraption
--不幸的是，这个按钮没有完成，而且坏了，因为它完全变成了黑色
Button - which unfortunately is unfinished and broken, as it renders completely black.
这里有一个修复的Contraption Button实际是什么样子的。这个
Here's a restoration of what the Contraption Button is actually meant to look like. This
按钮如果使用的话是完全不起作用的，由于我们不知道《传送门2》
button is entirely non-functional if used, and due to us not knowing what's going on internally
教育版的内部代码是怎样的，所以我们不知道它的作用，
on the code level of Portal 2's Educational Version, we don't know what it was meant to
只知道它很可能是和Contraption Cube一起使用的。
do other than the fact it was very likely to be used in conjunction with the Contraption Cube. And
是的--如果你想说Contraption Cube在正常的按钮上也能工作，那么它就不能
yes - the Contraption Cube works on normal buttons too if you're about to suggest that it doesn't.
教育版还为puzzlemaker增加了一个新项目--这就是Text Bubble
The Educational Version also adds one more new item to the puzzlemaker - This is the Text Bubble,
也被称为 "Text Node"。这并不完全是一个宇宙中的测试元素，
also known as a Text Node. This is not exactly an in-universe test element,
更多的是它是在关卡中留下注释的一种方式。 你可以在其中写下文字，然后 "播放 "这些文字
more that it is a way to leave notes in the level. You can write text in it and then “play” the text
在游戏中，就像你玩一个评论节点一样，文本出现的方式类似于字幕
ingame like you would play a Commentary Node, the text appears in a similar fashion to how subtitles
在屏幕上的格式，总共最多只有6行，
are formatted on your screen, and have a maximum of 6 lines total before the text bubble will just
在文本气泡直接拒绝显示任何进一步的内容之前，评论节点
outright refuse to display anything further. One main difference between Commentary Nodes
和文本气泡之间的一个主要区别是，你必须在文本气泡的附近才能激活它，
and Text Bubbles is that you have to be in the vicinity of the Text Bubble to activate it, while
而评论节点基本上可以从任何地方激活，只要你看着它
Commentary Nodes can be activated from basically anywhere so long as you are looking at it.
在我们进一步讨论游戏中的变化之前，我想提及
Before we move onto further ingame changes, I'd like to mention an interesting
教育版的puzzlemaker中跳板的一个有趣的特殊性
peculiarity with Aerial Faith Plates in the Educational Edition's puzzlemaker.
Valve增加了一个使用 "impulses "的选项，因此，与其简单地放置一个目标
Valve added an option to use ‘impulses', so rather than simply placing a target for the Faith Plate
让跳板射向你，不如调整跳板发射物体的力度和角度，
to shoot you towards, you adjust the force and angle that the Faith Plate will launch objects at,
这有点类似于你在Hammer中设置跳板的方式，
但不完全是，因为你仍然要在Hammer中设置一个目标
分别以牛顿和度数衡量。调节时，水平仪中没有目标点，
measured in newtons and degrees respectively. No target spot is made in the level when compiled,
据推测，这是由于跳板的这一
presumably this was due to the fact that this specific new
特定新功能是为了在物理课上使用
feature of Faith Plates was made to be used in physics classes.
现在我们已经进入游戏，教育版增加了两个新的机制，
Now that we're ingame, the Educational Version adds two new mechanics made to
是为了在我们要看的学习环境中使用。通过在选项中启用
be used in the learning environment that we're going to be looking at. By enabling
教育模式，我们可以获得一个秒表和物理学速度操纵器。
Education Mode in the options, we gain access to a stopwatch and physics speed manipulator.
很抱歉，录制的时候裁剪得不好
按J键，启动秒表计时器，K键停止计时器，L键复位，6键
By pressing J, we start the Stopwatch Timer, K to stop the timer, L to reset it, and 6 to toggle
在开和关之间切换，如果你在学校做过任何形式的物理学相关实验，
it between on and off, if you've ever done any form of physics related experiments in school,
你会知道计时是非常重要的，你几乎肯定使用秒表为物体计时，
you'd know that timing is very important and you almost certainly used a stopwatch to time objects,
传送门2的教育版用它自己的秒表做了这件事，
Portal 2's Educational Version does this exact thing with it's own stopwatch, and it's
而且它实际上是相当不错的。很快就跳回了益智游戏机。  快速跳回Puzzlemaker，
actually rather fascinating. Hopping back to the Puzzlemaker real quick,
所有的按钮实际上都有一个 "切换秒表 "的选项，
all buttons actually feature a “Toggle Stopwatch” option that will run the
只要它们被按下就会运行秒表，你真的可以看出
stopwatch for as long as they're pressed down, you can really tell the level of thought that
开发教育版的思想水平，无论如何，回到游戏中......
went into developing the Educational Version with neat quirks like that, anyways, back ingame…
传送门2教育版最后带来的是前面提到的
The final thing that Portal 2 Educational Version brings to the table is the aforementioned Physics
速度操纵器，这基本上是一个更方便的phys_timescale
Speed Manipulator, this is essentially a more user-friendly version of the phys_timescale
的命令的版本。它可以改变游戏里的物理速度，而且不影响玩家
command. It changes how fast physics in the world reacts, and doesn't affect the player.
按1设置为100%的速度，2设置为0%，3设置为50%，4设置为10%，
Pressing 1 sets it to 100% speed, 2 sets it to 0%, 3 sets it to 50%, 4 to 10%
5设置为1%。你可以用它来确保一旦
and 5 sets it to 1%. You can use this to basically ensure objects will drop
物体可能停留的平台被移除，物体将在同一时间下降
at the same time once the platform they may be resting on is removed.
我对这个东西玩得很开心，用人们无法想象的方式把方块发射出去，
I had a lot of fun actually playing around with this thing, launching cubes around in humanly
把物理速度设置为零来停止时间，基本上是把方块
impossible ways, setting the physics speed to zero to stop time and essentially sending cubes
通过无限循环的抛掷来建立速度。如果有人重新制作基本游戏《传送门2》的用户界面，
through an infinite loop of flings to build up speed. You could probably make a cool mod
你也许可以用这个概念制作一个很酷的mod，
concept out of this if anyone recreated the UI in base game Portal 2 honestly,
我甚至用暂停物理的想法做了一个快速的解谜，让我展示一下
I even made a quick puzzle with the idea of being able to pause physics, lemme show it off.
很完美，不是吗？
Pretty neat isn't it?
我想我们就快结束这段视频了，
I think we're just about getting close to wrapping up this video,
但在我们完全结束之前--教育版为我们准备了最后一个惊喜
but before we fully end it - Educational Version has one final surprise for us.
按住R键，我们就可以看到传送门2未使用的反馈平移菜单，
By holding down R, we get a proper peek at Portal 2's unused Feedback Ping Menu,
这是为Puzzlemaker计划的一个游戏测试系统，原本是
this was planned for the Puzzlemaker with the idea of a Playtest system that was originally going
要让Puzzlemaker通过整个系统来获得游戏测试的反馈，
to be used by puzzle creators to get playtest feedback on their puzzles through a whole system
但这是另一个视频的故事。这个反馈平移菜单基本上
that was canned, but that's a story for another video. This Feedback Ping Menu basically acts
与平移工具的作用相同，你可以突出显示对象，选择特定的平移反应
the same as the Ping Tool, you can highlight objects, choose specific ping responses,
整个作品为什么在教育版中重新启用了这一功能......谁也不知道，真的
the whole works. Why the hell this was reenabled in Educational Version is… anyone's guess really.
当然，我还可以谈更多，教育版似乎
There's certainly more I could've talked about, the Educational Version seems like it has its
有它自己的一堆未使用的、报废的和丢失的内容，但这是我仍在挖掘的东西
own heap of unused, scrapped and lost content but that's something I'm still digging into,
例如，Contraption Cube 在它的环上
有一个未使用的 "测光表"，我在HLMV中控制它。
另外，我还没打算用这些事实来使这段视频过于复杂化，
plus I didn't plan on overcomplicating this video with those facts just yet, this is a
这段视频主要是让人们了解《传送门2》的教育版是什么样的
video to mainly getting people informed about what Portal 2's Educational Version was like,
这对我个人来说当然是一种宣泄，因为我记得在我年轻的时候
it's certainly cathartic for me personally since I remember trying to campaign for my
曾试图为我的学校争取使用传送门教学项目，因为我认为
school to use the Teach With Portals program when I was younger just because I thought the
在学校使用传送门2学习是如此的酷。过了这么久
possibility of using Portal 2 in school and for learning was so cool. Actually playing
才玩这个版本的游戏，对我个人来说是非常有成就感的
this version of the game after so long is so god damned fulfilling to me personally.
这就是我今天的全部内容，在推特上关注我，
That's all I have for today folks, be sure to subscribe, follow me on Twitter and
原作者：Ossy Flawol  原视频标题：Portal 2's Educational Version - An Obscure Part of Valve's History
并在Patreon上支持我，
support me on Patreon if you want to really learn more obscure Portal content with me,
翻译/压制/字幕：HAF半个水果    翻译支持：DeepL  原视频上传时间：2022年7月25日
如果你想真正和我一起了解更多不为人知的传送门内容，请务必订阅！
because trust me - I still haven't scratched the surface. Anyways, stay safe y'all, peace!
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧
原始字幕来自YouTube，如有错漏，欢迎指正！
如有能力到YouTube支持原作者